Earl Browder Papers
Earl Browder Papers
- Writings
  - Articles
    - Undated (Box 50)
      Weekly Comment: The San Francisco Conference [2], 6/3/1945
      Weekly Comment: Senator Taft Opposes Foreign Trade, 4/15/1945
      Weekly Comment: Significance of Casablanca and Our Duties, 2/13/1943
      Weekly Comment: Some New Perspectives, 8/20/1944
      Weekly Comment: Some Pre-Election Confusionism, 6/4/1944
      Weekly Comment: Stop This Criminal Nonsense!, 3/18/1945
      Weekly Comment: Sumner Welles' Time For Decision
      Weekly Comment: The U.S. Army Kills the Red Bogey
      Weekly Comment: The Twilight of the Red Herring (incomplete)
      Weekly Comment: Watch Out for Dewey's Surprise, 10/29/1944
      Weekly Comment: The Western Front and the Communist Convention
      Weekly Comment: Wilkie's Growing Stature, 8/27/1944
      Weekly Comment: Who is Off The Beam?, 2/4/1945
      Weekly Comment: Why All the Double-Talk?, 2/11/1945
  - Books
    - America Encircled, 1952; 6 folders (Box 51)
    - The American Communists: A Threat to Trade Unionism?, 1946 (Box 52)
    - American Marxists and the War, 1942 (Box 52)
    - American Labor's Exceptional Road to Power, 1952 (Box 52)
    - The Anti-Marxism of W. Z. Foster, 1949 (Box 52)
    - Autobiography, "Memoirs" (Box 52)
    - Autobiography, "I Discovered America" (Box 52)
    - Autobiography, "A Political Autobiography", 4 folders of 19 (Box 52)
    - Autobiography, "A Political Autobiography", 8 folders of 19 (Box 53)
    - Autobiograph,y "A Political Autobiography", 7 folders of 19 (Box 54)
    - The Bankruptcy of Fosterism, 1950 (Box 54)
    - The Coming Soviet-German Alliance, 1952 (Box 54)
    - Confessions of a Peacemaker, 1949 (Box 54)
    - The Constitutional Crisis in the United States, 1937 (Box 54)
    - Contempt of Congress: The Trial of Earl Browder, 1950 (Box 54)
    - The Crisis in Socialism, 1956; 2 folders (Box 55)
    - Crisis of American Progressivism, 1951 (Box 55)
    - A Decade of American Marxism: 1933-1945 (Box 55)
    - Does Communism Point the Way?, 1938 (Box 55)
    - The Economics of All-Out War, 1942 (Box 55)
    - Education of an American Communist, 1947; 2 folders (Box 55)
    - Fighting For Peace (Box 56)
    - Havana Raises Pan-American Problems, 1940 (Box 56)
    - How the Jefferson School Has Bowdlerized Marxism, 1949 (Box 56)
    - In Defense of Communism: A Criticism of W.Z. Foster's 'New Route to Socialism' (Box 56)
    - Karl Marx and America, 1957 (Box 56)
    - Keynes Foster and Marx Pt II: Progress and Socialism, 1950 (Box 56)
    - Labor and Socialism in America, 1948 (Box 56)
    - Marx and America, 1958; 3 folders of 8 (Box 56)
    - Marx and America, 1958; 5 folders of 8 (Box 57)
    - Marxist Philosophy, 1946 (Box 57)
    - McCarthyism at High Tide, 1954 (Box 57)
    - Modern Resurrections and Miracles, 1950 (Box 57)
    - Munich, n.d. (Box 58)
    - My Dream of World History, 1945-1975 (Box 58)
    - My Visit to Beograd, 1958 (Box 58)
    - National Income, Consumer Welfare and Full Employment, 1941 (Box 58)
    - The New Moment in the Struggle Against War, 1940 (Box 58)
    - Parties and Issues in the 1948 Elections (Box 58)
    - The Postwar Crisis, 1948 (Box 58)
    - Peace is Possible, 1948 (Box 58)
    - Principles of Accounting for Co-Operators, 1918 (Box 58)
    - The Second Imperialist War (foreward) (Box 59)
    - Socialism in America, 1960 (Box 59)
    - Soviet-American Relations: Is It War or Peace?, 1945 (Box 59)
    - Teheran: Our Path in War and Peace, 1944; 3 folders (Box 59)
    - Tomorrow in the Making (Box 59)
    - Victory and After (Box 59)
    - The Way Out, n.d.; foreword (Box 60)
    - What Is Communism?, 1936 (Box 60)
    - What Price Victory?, 1943 (Box 60)
    - Will America Survive?, 1948; outline and preface (Box 60)
    - World Communism and American Foreign Policy, 1948 (Box 60)
    - World Communism and U.S. Foreign Policy invoices, 1948; 2 folders (Box 60)
    - Unidentified and fragments (Box 61)
  - Speeches
    See also Memorabilia: Sound recordings for recordings of Browder's speeches.
    - 1934 (Box 62)
      Fascism and war, 9/28/1934, Youth Congress, Chicago
    - 1935 (Box 62)
      Unemployment and Social Insurance, 1/6/1935, Congress for Unemployment Insurance, Washington, DC
      Statement, 2/19/1935, Senate Finance Committee Hearing, Washington, DC
      "This writer in the Class Struggle", 4/26/1935, First Congress of American Writers
      Economic crisis and the intellectual world, 4/26/1935?, First Congress of American Writers [?]
      Eulogy for Henri Barbusse, 9/7/1935, Funeral of Henri Barbusse, Paris
      Debate with Norman Thomas, 11/27/1935, Madison Square Garden
      Ethiopia and Mussolini, 12/12/1935, St Nicholas Place
      How can America keep out of the next world war?, ?/?/1935, unknown (CPUSA?)
    - 1936 Jan-Jun (Box 62)
      Henri Barbusse, 1/4/1936, Third U.S. Congress Against War and Fascism
      Opening statement, 1/11/1936, Debate with Norman Thomas, Cleveland
      "Abraham Lincoln and the Crisis of 1936", 2/12/1936, Springfield, IL
      "The Communist Position in 1936" published version, 3/5/1936, CBS Radio broadcast
      extracts from defense of CPUSA, 5/30/1936, National Conference of Farmer-Labor Parties, Chicago
      CPUSA pledges support of Farmer-Labor Party, 5/30/1936, Farmer-Labor Party Conference, Morrison Hotel, Chicago
      Democracy or Fascism?, 6/24/1936, Ninth National Convention CPUSA, New York
      CP is a legal party and defends its legality, 6/24/1936, Ninth National Convention CPUSA, New York
      Acceptance speech, 6/24/1936, Ninth National Convention CPUSA, New York
    - 1936 Jul-Dec (Box 62)
      Campaign speech, 7/4/1936, American Youth Congress, Cleveland
      Campaign speech, 7/10/1936, WGY Radio broadcast, Schenectady, NY
      "Platform and Policy of the Communist Party in 1936", 7/17/1936, Institute of Public Affairs, University of Virginia
      Presidential campaign speech, 8/18/1936, Radio broadcast, Butte, MT
      Campaign speech, 8/27/1936, Coney Island Velodrome
      Campaign speech, 8/28/1936, Radio broadcast, NBC
      Civil Rights, 9/15/1936, Nassau-Suffolk Socialist Party
      Press conference re: Law suit against Tampa, FL for not allowing campaign appearance, 9/17/1936, unknown
      "Old Age Pensions and Unemploymet Insurance", 10/2/1936, Radio broadcast campaign speech
      Radio interview about 1936 campaign, 10/?/1936, Interviewed by Cedric Foster
      Campaign speech, 10/27/1936, Olympia Arena, Detroit
      Red scare in the 1936 campaign, 10/29/1936, Radio broadcast, Buffalo, NY
      Campaign speech, 11/2/1936, Madison Square Garden and Radio broadcast on NBC Blue
      "Issues of the 1936 Election Campaign", 11/?/1936, Radio broadcast
      Interview, ?/?/1936, Women's International League, New York
      Issues in the 1936 campaign, ?/?/1936, unknown
      Negro rights in the South - Campaign speech, ?/?/1936, unknown
    - 1937 (Box 62)
      Lenin tribute, 1/20/1937, Lenin Memorial Meeting (CPUSA), New York
      "The Brazilian Struggle for Liberalism", 2/2/1937, WNEW Radio broadcast
      "Trotskyism and World Peace", 2/5/1937, Madison Square Garden
      "In Memory of Our Heroes of the Lincoln Battalion Who Died for Democracy", 5/30/1937, Memorial Day speech
      Fascism and war, 6/4/1937, Second Congress of American Writers
      Fascism and war, 6/27/1937, C.C. Plenum Mexico
      Peace, 7/?/1937, Radio broadcast to World Fellowship of Faiths Symposium
      Spain, 7/19/1937, Meeting for Spain
      "Issues of the 1New York City Municipal Elections", 7/29/1937, Radio broadcast
      Inauguration of a chain of Communist daily newspapers, 8/24/1937, Press interview
      "For Progressive Unity in the New York Elections", 8/26/1937, Velodrme Brooklyn and broadcast on WMCA, WNEW, WAXR, and WINS
      Eighteenth Anniversary of the Communist Party, 8/27/1937, unknown CP meeting
      "The Eighteenth Anniversary of the Communist Party", 9/1/1937, NBC Blue broadcast
      "The Eighteenth Anniversary of the Communist Party", 9/13/1937, Communist Party Convention Madison Square Garden
      "Threat of Fascism in Latin America", 10/2/1937, Meeting in Park Place
      "For a Common Front Against the Warmakers", 10/8/1937, Eighth Dominion Convention CP Canada, Toronto
      "Twenty Years of Soviet Power", 10/10/1937, Eighth Dominion Convention CP Canada, Toronto
      "Summing Up the New York Election Issues", 10/30/1937, unknown
      Twentieth Anniversary of the Soviet Union, 11/?/1937, Twentieth Anniversary Meeting
      CP goals, 11/19/1937, unknown (CP)
      "Next Steps In Dfense of the Spanish republic", 12/9/1937, Hippodrome, New York
      "The Current Economic Crisis--Its Cause and Cure", 12/12/1937, WEVD Radio broadcast presented by NYC Boars of Education
    - 1938 Mar-Jun (Box 63)
      "Concerted Action or Isolation as the Path to Peace?", 3/3/1938, Carolina Political Union, Chapel Hill, NC
      "Lessons of the Moscow Trials", 3/18/1938, Hippodrome, New York
      "Bloc of Rights and Trotzkyists", 3/20/1938, unknown (CP)
      "Communism in Theory and Practice", 3/24/1938, Town Hall
      "Communism in Theory and Practice", 3/24/1938, Lecture for Current Political and Economic Issues, New York University
      War and Fascism, 4/6/1938, Orchestra Hall. Chicago
      introduction for Earl Browder, 4/24/1938, Public Service Forum
      Debate with Frederick J. Libby, 5/4/1938, Madison Square Garden
      "A Communist Message to Catholics", 5/8/1938, WCBM Radio broadcast, Baltimore
      Opening remarks, 5/26/1938, Tenth National Convention CPUSA
      "Marxism and the American Tradition", 5/28/1938, Tenth Natitional Convention CPUSA, Carnegie Hall
      Statement of Earl Browder, 6/29/1938, McNaboe Committee (NY State Legislature)
    - 1938 Jul-Dec (Box 63)
      American principles and Communism, 7/4/1938, July 4th Picnic (CP?)
      "Which Way for America--Democracy or Fascism?", 8/25/1938, San Francisco
      Report, 8/26/1938, California State Executive Committee (CP)
      Communists and the New deal, 9/3/1938, Frye Hotel banquet, Seattle, WA
      "The Communists Defend Democracy and Peace", 9/5/1938, KIRO Radio broadcast for Labor day, Seattle, WA
      Party Building, 9/6/1938, Party Builders' Conference CPUSA
      1938 elections, 9/14/1938, Manhattan Oddfellows Temple
      "The World Issue -- Defend Democracy and Peace", 9/15/1938, Coney Island Velodrome
      Fascism, Munich Pact, Spain, 1938 elections, 10/27/1938, Jamaica Arena, New York
      The Elections and the International Situation", 11/1/1938, WENR Radio broadcast, Chicago
      US and the world situation, 11/4/1936, Press interview, Chicago
      1938 elections, 11/6/1938, Boston Arena (CP)
      "On theTwenty-First Anniversary of the Soviet Union", 11/14/1938, Madison Square Garden [CPUSA?[
      Report to National Committee, 12/3/1938, National Committee CPUSA
      "Theory as a Guide to Action", 12/16/1938, Workers' School 15th Anniversary, Mecca Temple
      "Three Years Application of the Program of the Seventh World Congress", ?/?/1938, unknown CP meeting
    - 1939 Jan-Jun (Box 63)
      "Is America Menaced by Foreign Propaganda", 1/19/1939, Town Meeting of the Air
      Fifteenth anniversary of the death of Lenin, 1/20/1939, Lenin Memorial Meeting (CP?), Philadelphia, PA
      "Defend the Social and national Security of the American People", 1/24/1939, Cincinnati, Ohio
      Fascism and war, 1/31/1939, Seventh Congress CP Mexico, Mexico city
      "The Economics of Communism: The Soviet Economy in its World Relations", 2/27/1939, Town Hall
      "A Communist Speaks to Catholics, Jews and Protestants", 3/5/1939, Community Church, Boston
      Report on 18th Congress of CPSU, 3/16/1939, unknown (CP)
      Transcript of testimony by Browder and others NY Senate Un-American Activities Committee, 3/27/1939, Hotel New Yorker, New York
      "Close Ranks for the Greater Battle Ahead", 4/2/1939, Freiheit Celebration, Hippodrome, New York
      "American democracy is Threatened by Fascism and War", 4/3/1939, Chicago
      Nadezhda Krupskaya, 4/7/1939, Krupskaya Memorial Meeting (CP)
      "America's Foreign Policy and the Struggle for World Peace", 4/21/1939, Brooklyn Academy of Music
      Report to National Committee, 5/6/1939, National Committee meeting, New York
      Fascism and war, 5/11/1939, 10th Convention YCL
      "The Communist Writer at the Writers' Congress", 5/16/1939, Third Congress of American Writers, Carnegie Hall
      Acknowledgement of CP representatives from other countries, 5/17/1939, National Committee [CPUSA?]
      "What is the Road to Economic Recovery?", 5/23/1939, Radio broadcast, Denver, CO
      Interview, 5/31/1939, Radio broadcast, Los Angeles, CA
      "What is the Road to Economic Recovery?", 6/5/1939, Radio broadcast, KGA Radio, Spokane, WA, KOMO Radio, Seattle, WA
    - 1939 Jul-Dec (Box 63)
      "United States and the Soviet Union in World Affairs", 7/5/1939, Institute of Public Affairs, University of Virginia
      Interview, 8/23/1939, unknown
      Earl Browder interview, 8/26/1939, NBC Radio broadcast
      "Finding the Road to Peace", 8/29/1939, WINS Radio broadcast, New York
      Report on the Twentieth Anniversary, 9/1/1939, National Committee CPUSA, Chicago
      Announcement of letter from CPUSA to FDR supporting his policy, 9/11/1939, Madison Square Garden
      "On the Issue of Revision of the So-Called neutrality Law", 9/14/1939, National Committee CPUSA
      Press interview, 9/18/1939, New York Post and New York World Telegram
      "Youth and the Impreialist War", 9/28/1939, Mass Meeting of the YCL. Royal Windsor Hotel, New York
      War in Europe, 9/29/1939, Town Hall, Philadelphia
      Civil liberties, 10/14/1939, Conference on Civil Liberties, New York
      Legal charges against him, 10/24/1938, Statement to the Press
      "Twenty-Two Years of Socialism", 11/5/1939, Symphony Hall, Boston
      "Socialism, War and America", 11/13/1939, Madison Square Garden
      War in Europe, 11/28/1939, Yale Peace Council
      War in Europe, 12/14/1939, M.I.T. Peace Federation
      Moissaye J. Olgin tribute, 12/18/1939, Olgin Memorial Meeting, Madison Square Garden
    - 1940 Jan-Jun (Box 64)
      14th District New York elections, 1/30/1940, Non-Partisan Youth Symposium, Manhattan Plaza
      14th District New York elections, 2/1/1940, Central Plaza, New York
      Campaign speech, 2/5/1940, Tenant's League Symposium, Church of All Nations
      14th District New York elections, 2/5/1940, WCNW Radio broadcast
      American principles and Communism, 2/9/1940, Lincol/Lenin Memorial Meeting, Philadelphia
      1940 elections, 2/17/1940, National Committee CPUSA
      Imperialist war and Finland, 3/31/1940, Boston
      "War Plans of Roosevelt and Wall Street", 5/3/1940, YCL Meeting, Royal Windsor Hotel, New York
      Report, 5/30/1940, Eleventh National Convention CPUSA, New York
      Presidential Nomination acceptance, 6/2/1940, CP Nominating Convention, New York
      Closing statement at National Convention?, 6/2/1940?, CP Nominating Convention, New York ?
      Campaign speech, 6/2/1940, CBS Radio broadcast
    - 1940 Sep-Nov (Box 64)
      "Mexican situation", 9/7/1940, Press statement
      "The Most Peculiar Election Campaign in the History of the Republic", 9/8/1940, Olympic Auditorium, Los Angeles, CA
      "Women in the Struggle against War and Reaction", 9/19/1940, New York
      Campaign speech, 9/24/1940, Mass Meeting, Madison Square Garden, broadcast on NBC Blue
      Campaign speech, 9/25/1940, Radio broadcast, NBC Blue
      "Have We Free Elections in Pennsylvania?", 10/4/1940, WOR Radio broadcast, New York
      "What Roosevelt and Willkie Offer to American Youth", 10/4/1940, Mutual Broadcasting Radio broadcast
      "An American Foreign-Policy for Peace", 10/6/1940, Boston
      "An American Foreign-Policy for Peace", 10/10/1940, CBS Radio broadcast
      Campaign speech, 10/17/1940, Brooklyn Academy of Music
      Tribute to John Reed, 10/20/1940, Manhattan Center, New York
      1940 election campaign commercial for CPNY candidates, 10/27/1940, Radio
      "Shall it be War for America?", 10/29/1940, Mutual Broadcasting Radio broadcast
      1940 election, 10/?/1940, unknown
      "Only the Working Class Can build America", 11/3/1940, Madison Square Garden
      Report, 11/16/1940, Special National Convention CPUSA, New York
      "The 1940 Elections and the Next Task", 11/16/1940, National Committee CPUSA
      "In Memory of a Great Jewish Leader", 11/23/1940, Moissaye Olgin Memorial. New York
      Statement before the Committee on Elections, ?/?/1940, NY State Legislature
    - 1941 (Box 64)
      Death of Harry Gannes, 1/5/1941, Public statement
      "What Is the Way Out of the Imperialist War?", 1/13/1941, Lenin Memorial Meeting (CP), Madison Square Garden
      In honor of William Z. Foster, 3/17/1941, William Z. Foster's 60th birthday
    - 1942 Feb-Aug (Box 64)
      US/Soviet cooperation in the War, 2/12/1942, Lincoln/Lenin day
      "Victory Must Be Won", 7/2/1942, Madison Square Garden
      "The Economics of All-Out War", 8/29/1942, NY CP Convention
      1942 New York elections, 8/30/1942, NY CP Nominating Convention, Manhattan Center
    - 1942 Sep-Nov (Box 64)
      Report, 9/17/1942, Daily Worker Council Meeting, Webster Hall, New York
      Second front, 9/24/1942, Second Front Rally, Union Square, New York
      "When Do we Begin to Fight?", 10/2/1942, Manhattan Center, New York
      "This is the will of the people", 10/4/1942, Second Front Now Rally, Public Auditorium, Cleveland, OH
      Oklahoma book banning case, 10/9/1942, Defense on Home Front banquet, Hotel Commodore
      Re-discovering America, 10/11/1942, The Worker
      US policy toward China, 10/12/1942, Press statement
      US/Soviet cooperation in the War, 10/16/1942, Workers' School
      1942 New York elections, 10/18/1942, Golden Gate Ballroom, New York
      Elections must smoke out defeatists, 11/1/1942, Madison Square Garden, WQXR
      Appraisal of 1942 election results, 11/4/1942, unknown
      CP and the War effort, 11/12/1942, WJLB radio Detroit
      "Centralized Control of War Production", 11/28/1942, Institute on Problems of the War, Hotel astor, New York
      Trade Unions and the War, 12/12/1942, "Speech to Trade Union Comrades"
      National unity, 11/30/1942, Banquet (CP?)
      Education, 12/18/1942, Workers' School
    - 1943 Jan-May (Box 65)
      Russia, The United States and the Communist Party", circa 1943, unknown
      "France is Uniting Against Hitler", 1/?/1943, Script for Browder's radio program "Background of the News"
      "The Conference at Casablanca", 1/?/1943, Script for Browder's radio program "Background of the News"
      Casablanca Conference, 1/?/1943, unknown
      Tribute to Lenin, 1/11/1943, Lenin Memorial Meeting (CP), Madison Square Garden
      Labor and the War, 1/17/1943, Los Angeles, CA
      Labor and the War, 1/20/1943, KPO Radio broadcast
      US/Soviet cooperation in the War, 3/3/1943, Yale Political Union debate
      Interview, 3/3/1943, Lilian Rixey of Life
      "Free the Political Prisoners in North Africa", 3/4/1943, Manhattan Center, New York
      "Is Communism a Menace?", 3/21/1943, New Masses debate with George Sokolsky, Manhattan Center, New York
      Ehrlich-Alter Case, 4/1/1943, Aperion Manor, New York
      "Jefferson and the People's Revolution", 4/9/1943, Jefferson Bi-Centennial Commemoration, Cosmopolitan Opera House, New York
      "The Miners' Strike -- Its Lessons", 5/14/1943, Manhattan Center, New York
      Questions and Answers, 5/14/1943
    - 1943 Jun-Sep (Box 65)
      "Anti-Semitism in The United States and How to combat It", 6/2/1943, unknown
      "The Artist and the War", 6/23/1943, unknown
      Should the Communist Party be liquidated, 7/11/1943, WLIB
      Reaction of the press to Browder's Chicago speech, 9/1943, Press statement
      "The Quebec Conference and the future of the Anglo-Soviet-American Coalition", 9/2/1943, Manhattan Center, New York
      "Can We Win the War This Year?", 9/23/1943, Campaign rally for Peter Caccione, New York
      "A Talk About the Party" (2 different versions), 9/25/1943, Informal address to CP members, Chicago
      "Can We Make 1943 The Decisive Year of the War?", 9/26/1943, Civic Opera house, Chicago
    - 1943 Oct-Dec (Box 65)
      Peter Caccione campaign, 10/5/1943, St George Hotel, Brooklyn
      "Young People Facing the Future", 10/15/1943, Young Communist League Convention, Manhattan Center, New york
      1943 election campaign New York, 10/18/1943, Manhattan Center, New York (CP)
      1944 election campaign New York, 10/20/1943, Bronx Winter Garden, New York
      Phialdelphia Mayoral election, 10/22/1943, Philadelphia
      "On the 26th Anniversary of Soviet Power and the 10th Anniversary of Soviet-American Diplomatic Relations", 11/?/1943, unknown
      Negro people and the war, 11/19/1943, Workers School
      Teheran Declaration, 12/12/1943, Rakosci Hall, Bridgeport, CT
      "America Must Apply the Moscow Conference Policy in Italy", 12/19/1943, Cooper Union, New York
      George Dimitroff, 12/22/1943, Dimitroff Commemoration Meeting, Carnegie Hall
    - 1944 Jan-Apr (Box 65)
      Report on Theheran Conference, 1/7/1944, National Committee CPUSA
      Summary remarks, 1/9/1944, Plenum CP
      Interview, 1/12/1944, Mr. Moody of Australian Consolidated Press
      Tribute to Art Young, 1/27/1944, Memorial Meeting for Art Young, Manhattan Center, New York
      Summary remarks, 1/29/1944, Ohio CP Party Builders' Conference, Cleveland
      National unity, 1/30/1944, Cleveland
      Teheran Conference, 2/13/1944, Symphony Hall, Boston
      1944 elections, 2/13/1944, unknown (CP), Boston
      Interview, 2/22/1944, Peter Kihss of the New York Herald Tribune
      Teheran concord, 2/24/1944, Bronx winter Garden, New York [CP?]
      "Why America is Interested in the Chinese Communists", 3/13/1944, Shaghai Tiffin Club, New York
      Interview, 3/15/1944, Harold Lavine of P M
      "What Would Lincoln Do?", 4/7/1944, WWJ Radio broadcast, Detroit, Michigan
      Post-War economy, 4/12/1944, Waterfron Section CPUSA meeting
      Tribute to Jews of the Warsaw Ghetto, 4/20/1944, Parkway Theater, Brooklyn
    - 1944 May-Jun (Box 66)
      Introductory remarks, 5/20/1944, Twelfth National Convention CPUSA, New York
      Remarks introducing motion to dissolve the Communist Party, 5/20/1944, Twelfth National Convention CPUSA, New York
      Concluding remarks, 5/22/1944, Twelfth National Convention CPUSA, New York
      Press interview, 5/22/1944, New York
      Teheran Conference, 5/23/1944, WEAF Radio broadcast
      "For Victory, A Lasting Peace, and a Prosperous United America", 5/23/1944, Madison Square Garden
      "Communists in the Public Service", 6/4/1944, CBS Radio broadcast
      Dissolution of CPUSA and forming of Communist Political Association, 6/5/1944, unknown
      "The War and the Elections", 6/11/1944, Pittsburgh, PA
      Labor movement, 6/12/1944, Meeting of Pittsburgh Trade Unionists
      "Can America Have Full Production After the War?", 6/13/1944, Abraham Lincoln School Symposium, Chicago
    - 1944 Sep-Dec (Box 66)
      "The War and the Elections", 9/24/1944, Chicago Stadium
      "The War and the Elections" (typescript and published version), 9/28/1944, Madison Square Garden
      1944 elections, 9/30/1944, First Conference of Morning Freiheit Association
      "Economic Problems of War and Peace", 10/6/1944, Symphony Hall, Boston
      1944 elections, 11/19/1944, Worker Conference, Fraternal Clubhouse
      "Post-Election Problems", 11/26/1944, unknown
      1944 elections, 11/29/1944, unknown
      Greece, 12/8/1944, Workers' Meeting, Manhattan Center, New York